brandsdistribution.com 2016-05-08

# Privacy Policy | Brandsdistribution.com

Our webstore uses cookies to offer a better user experience and we consider that you are accepting their use if you keep browsing brandsdistribution.com. X

This Privacy Policy explains what type of personal data we are collecting, how the personal data are used, to whom and in which situations such personal data are disclosed and how you can request the modification or deletion of your personal data that we hold about you. Also, as our website is using cookies, the Cookies section hereof offers you the necessary details in relation hereto. 

This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and is a part of our Terms and Conditions. Therfore by accepting our Terms and Conditions, you accept this Privacy Policy. 

In order to complete any purchase transaction on our website you will be asked to subscribe by completing the Form available on our website and which requires various personal data. 

When completing the Form, you will be asked to indicate your e-mail address, your complete name, your phone number and your gender, the data of your bank accounts and/or card, as well as any other personal information you wish to provide to us. 

Please note that these are mandatory information requested from you. Whenever a section of the Form is requested as mandatory, such section will be followed by the sign*. The non-completion of such section does not allow you to finalize the subscription on our website. 

The personal data requested in the form available on our website can be used by IDT for the following purposes: 

  * To create your personal account at IDT and to identify you as a user of our website;
  * To process your orders via our online services and to facilitate your transactions;
  * To send you text message and e-mail notifications of delivery status;
  * To send you marketing offers such as newsletters and catalogues either by text messages, phone calls, e-mails or by post;
  * To contact you in the event of any problems with the delivery of your items;
  * To offer you customer support relating to the products and services available on our website;
  * To answer your queries and to inform you of new or changed products and/or services;
  * To analyze your personal data in order to provide you with relevant marketing offers and information;
  * To validate that you are of legal age for shopping online;
  * To send you surveys in order to give you a possibility to influence our offer and services.

Also, by requesting such data we want to ensure the proper functioning of our website and services and to be able to improve our website and services. Our main purpose is to personalize your experience on our website. 

We connect your information, including personal data, your usage history etc. in order to provide you tailored promotions and marketing offers, to improve the content of the site for you and/or to determine your preferences. 

We mention that we may connect information collected from you through different means or at different times, and use such information obtained from other sources, including third parties. In order to do so, it is sometimes necessary to share this information with other business partners we are working with, such as companies that perform marketing services and other business operations for us. 

We will only keep your data for as long as necessary to carry out our services to you or for as long as we are required by law. After this, your personal data will be deleted. However, we cannot remove your data when there is a legal storage requirement, such as book-keeping rules or when there are other legal grounds to keep the data, such as an ongoing contractual relationship. 

We may also disclose your personal data to any governmental, regulatory and/or law enforcement authorities and agencies, to the extent disclosure is required or authorized by law and anytime we believe it is necessary or appropriate to comply with any law, regulation or other governmental request, in order to operate our website properly or to protect and defend our rights against any illegal activity. 

We may also share your personal data with our group companies, therefore we and/or our group companies may send you information about their products and services or whatever other information they may consider of interest for you. 

If you consent, we may also share your personal data with third parties (who are not group companies) so that we and/or those third parties may send you information about their products and/or services and any other information they may consider of interest for you. Note that such third parties may have different privacy practices, therefore IDT is not responsible for any aspect in relation with or which results from thereto. 

Our website may contain links or references to websites of our group companies or third parties, and their privacy policies may differ; therefore, please be aware of this aspect and read their corresponding privacy policies. We mention that we have no control over any other websites than our website, therefore we are not liable for any aspects that are connected with or may result from such other websites. 

The security of your personal data is a very important aspect for us. Therefore, we use our best efforts to take appropriate measures and to protect again any unauthorized access to or loss, misuse, disclosure of your personal data. In this respect, we implement generally accepted standards of technology security. 

However, given that there is no perfect security on the internet and no data transmission over internet can be deemed to be 100% secure, we cannot guarantee that any information and data stored on our servers or provided to or from a user will be protected from unauthorized access. 

By agreeing to this privacy policy, you agree not to hold us responsible for any breach of security. 

You acknowledge that we may need to host, store or transfer your personal data outside of your country of residency. Although we cannot guarantee the same level of protection of your personal data as may be ensured in the country of our headquarters, we shall use our best efforts to protect your personal data. Please note that however, we cannot be held liable for a security violation that occurs during or in relation to such a transfer. 

IDT declares and undertakes that it shall comply with all your rights granted by the Italian Law (Legislative Decree No. 196/2003) on the protection of personal data. In this respect, you may alter your data or request that it be deleted at any time, by sending a request in this respect to info@brandsdistribution.com at any time.

### COOKIES

This section refers to the cookies and web pages operated by IDT. 

### What is a cookie?

A cookie is a small text file (letters and numbers) that a website places in your PC, telephone or any other device, with information about your navigation on that website. The cookies are installed by request issued by the web-server to a browser (ex: Internet Explorer, Chrome) and does not contain any software, spyware or virus programs and cannot access information from the hardware of the user. 

### What are cookies used for on this website?

Cookies are a part of our website functions, having as main purpose to improve your navigational experience and to sustain the efforts of IDT to offer the best services for his users. The information collected in the cookies allows us to improve the website and to adapt its content to the user’s preferences and individual needs, to improve the result of the searches etc. The cookies used by the website are solely associated to anonymous users and their computers and do not provide personal details on users. The cookies used on the website are, in all cases, of a temporary nature, used solely to improve the efficiency of the last transmission. 

### What type of cookies are used on this website?

Our website uses the following types of cookies: 

**Technical cookies**

These cookies allow the user to browse the Website and use functions such as the shopping basket or Wishlist. 

**Analytical cookies**

IDT uses analytics cookies to calculate the number of users who visit the website and are registered. These cookies make it possible to measure and analyze the way in which users browse the website. This information allows IDT to continually improve its services and the shopping experience of users of the website. 

**Preference cookies**

Whenever users are browsing or shopping on the website, the site will remember their preferences (for example, their location or preferred language). Thanks to these cookies, we are able to offer users a simple, more convenient and personalized browsing experience. 

**Advertising cookies**

These cookies are used to show advertisements that are relevant to users and helps IDT to measure the effectiveness of its advertising campaigns. When browsing on the website, users accept that IDT will download these types of cookies on their devices and will consult when the user visits the website in the future. 

### Who uses the information stored in cookies?

The information stored in cookies on our website is used exclusively by us, with the exception of those identified further on as "third party cookies", which are used and managed by external bodies that provide us with services requested by us to improve our services and the user's experience when navigating our website. The main services for which these "third party cookies" are used are to obtain statistics on access and to secure payment transactions carried out. 

### How can I avoid using cookies on this website?

If you prefer to avoid using cookies on this website, having considered the previous limitations, you will first need to disable cookies in your browser, and secondly, delete saved cookies in your browser associated with this website. You can carry out the option of not using cookies at any moment. 

### How do I disable and delete the use of cookies?

You can delete, restrict or block cookies from this website at any time by modifying the configuration of your browser. While the configuration of every browser is different, cookies configuration is usually carried out in the "Preferences" or "Tools" menu. For more details about the configuration of cookies in your browser, please check your browser's "Help" menu. 

### How can I avoid using cookies on this website?

If you prefer to avoid using cookies on this website, you will first need to disable cookies in your browser. Please note that if you choose to disable cookies, you will not be able to take advantage of all our features and you may not be able to access certain functions of our website. 

### Final provisions

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so please review it frequently on this website. If we make any changes, we have no obligation to expressly notify you by email or post a notice on the site’s homepage. Therefore, we encourage you to read our revised Privacy Policy from time to time. The provision of personal data to IDT by the users is not mandatory. At any moment, you may request freely the modification and/or deletion of their personal data from the website database. By using our website, you expressly accept our Privacy Policy.
